(yue)粵文字幕:
www.cantocaptions.com
(en) Cantonese subtitles:
(yue)（遙遠嘅大陸北方盡頭）
(en) (The northern end of the distant continent)
(yue)（我抵達咗被世人稱為天國嘅地方）
(en) (I have arrived at the place known by the world as the Kingdom of Heaven)
(yue)（"靈魂長眠之地"）
(en) (The land where souls sleep in eternal peace)
(yue)（嗰度係個聚集咗好多靈魂嘅地方）
(en) (That is the place where many souls are gathered)
(yue)（我同過去嘅戰友對話）
(en) (I converse with my comrades of the past)
(yue)（大魔法使弗蘭梅）
(en) (Grand Magician Franmei)
(yue)芙莉蓮
(en) Flilian
(yue)已經可以見到皇都喇
(en) We can already see the imperial capital.
(yue)我哋幾個同勇者一齊凱旋而歸
(en) The few of us, along with the hero, return in triumph.
(yue)全國上下而家一定好興奮
(en) The whole country is surely very excited right now.
(yue)返到去之後，就要開始揾嘢做喇
(en) After returning, we must start finding something to do.
(yue)乜你已經開始考慮緊呢樣嘢嗱？
(en) What, have you already started thinking about that?
(yue)呢樣嘢好緊要㗎
(en) That is very important.
(yue)就算我哋已經打贏咗魔王都要繼續生活
(en) Even after defeating the Demon King, we must continue living.
(yue)之後落嚟嘅人生仲有好長㗎
(en) The life ahead of us is still very long.
(yue)要揾嘢做
(en) We need to find something to do.
(yue)如果份工可以隨時飲酒就好喇
(en) It would be great if the job allowed for drinking anytime.
(yue)你唔係僧侶嚟咩？
(en) Aren't you a monk?
(yue)噉講又係𠸏
(en) That's just like you.
(yue)芙莉蓮，你跟住落嚟嘅人生
(en) Flilian, the life that lies ahead for you
(yue)一定會比我哋可以想象得到嘅
(en) will certainly be beyond what we can imagine
(yue)更加漫長得多啊嗬？
(en) much longer, huh?
(yue)《葬送的芙莉蓮》
(en) “The Funeral of Flilian”
(yue)勇者欣梅爾
(en) Hero Xinmel
(yue)戰士艾冉
(en) Warrior Airan
(yue)僧侶海塔
(en) Monk Haita
(yue)魔法使芙莉蓮
(en) Mage Flilian
(yue)你哋今次成功打敗咗魔王做得好好
(en) You all did a great job defeating the Demon King this time.
(yue)從此，世界將會迎嚟和平嘅時代
(en) Henceforth, the world will enter an era of peace.
(yue)聽講國王陛下
會整我哋嘅雕像放喺廣場嗰度啊
(en) I heard that His Majesty the King will commission statues of us to be placed in the square.
(yue)不過，個雕像究竟可唔可以真實還原到
我呢個咁俊俏不凡嘅樣呢？
(en) However, can the statue truly replicate my exceptionally handsome looks?
(yue)講真我好有保留囖
(en) Honestly, I have my reservations.
(yue)佢哋班人真係現實
(en) Those people are really down-to-earth.
(yue)開始旅程嗰陣
明明只係畀咗十個銅幣我哋咋
(en) At the beginning of our journey, they only gave us ten copper coins.
(yue)好喇，算數啦，芙莉蓮
(en) Alright, it's a deal, Flilian.
(yue)橫掂而家可以噉樣免費任飲酒
(en) Now, you can freely drink without charge like this.
(yue)噉樣已經夠啦，係咪啊？
(en) Isn't that enough?
(yue)你個酒肉和尚
(en) You meat-eating monk.
(yue)旅程已經完結喇
(en) The journey has come to an end.
(yue)講得啱啊
(en) That's right.
(yue)我哋嘅冒險到呢度終於都完喇
(en) Our adventure has finally ended here.
(yue)已經十年喇
(en) It's been ten years.
(yue)喺呢段時間發生咗好多事
(en) A lot has happened during these years.
(yue)我記得出發嗰一日
(en) I remember the day we departed.
(yue)欣梅爾同艾冉對國王陛下不敬
(en) Xinmel and Airan were disrespectful to His Majesty the King.
(yue)爭啲被處死
(en) They nearly faced execution.
(yue)一唔小心我哋嘅冒險可能會喺嗰度完
(en) Had we not been cautious, our adventure might have ended there.
(yue)郁手
(en) Move hand
(yue)海塔仲試過因為宿醉一啲用都冇
(en) Haita even once was completely incapacitated by a hangover.
(yue)連路都行唔到啊
(en) He couldn't even walk.
(yue)你塊面青到好似不死族噉喎，冇嘢吖嘛？
(en) Your face is as pale as that of the undead; is something wrong?
(yue)-唔得喇
-都估到你㗎喇
(en) - No way.
- I knew it.
(yue)佢每個禮拜都會有一次醉到噉
(en) He gets that drunk once every week.
(yue)喺呢方面嘅話，我就好優秀
(en) In that aspect, I'm truly excellent.
(yue)-你爭啲畀寶箱怪食咗嗰陣
-好黑啊，好得人驚啊
(en) - When you were almost eaten by the treasure chest monster,
- it was pitch dark and terrifying.
(yue)我哋有諗過抌低你㗎
(en) We even thought about taking you down.
(yue)-同你講咗好多次係陷阱啦，仲中招
-你哋唔好企喺度快啲過嚟幫下我啦，好驚
(en) - We told you countless times it was a trap, but you still fell for it.
- Don't just stand there; come help me quickly, I'm terrified.
(yue)-蠢成咁不如抌低佢喇
-唔好，唔好食我啊
(en) - You're so foolish, might as well take him down.
- No, don't, don't eat me!
(yue)真係吖
(en) Really.
(yue)淨係諗到啲搞笑嘅回憶啊
(en) All I can recall are these hilarious memories.
(yue)不過真係好開心啊
(en) But it truly brings me joy.
(yue)我好慶幸可以同你哋一齊冒險係真㗎
(en) I am truly grateful to have adventured with you all.
(yue)冇錯，講得啱啊
(en) That's right, exactly.
(yue)雖然呢段冒險嘅時間有啲短
(en) Although this adventure was somewhat short,
(yue)你話有啲短？你喺度講咩啊？
(en) You say it's short? What are you even saying?
(yue)成十年喎
(en) It's been ten years!
(yue)你睇下海塔，已經由後生仔變咗做大叔喇
(en) Look at Haita; he has transformed from a young lad into an old man.
(yue)你噉講嘢㗎？
(en) Is that what you're saying?
(yue)佢本來就係大叔
(en) He was always an old man.
(yue)連你都噉講？
(en) Even you say that?
(yue)差唔多要開始喇
(en) It's almost time to begin.
(yue)好似係叫半世紀流星，係咪啊？
(en) It appears to be called the half-century meteor, doesn't it?
(yue)50年先會出現一次嘅流星雨
(en) A meteor shower that occurs only once every 50 years.
(yue)好啱用嚟做揭開呢個和平時代嘅序幕啊
(en) It's ideal for ushering in this era of peace.
(yue)真係好靚啊
(en) It's truly beautiful.
(yue)喺呢個城鎮好難睇得清啊
(en) In this town, it's difficult to see clearly.
(yue)我而家喺度感動緊㗎
(en) I am deeply moved right now.
(yue)唔好破壞個氣氛啦
(en) Don't ruin the mood.
(yue)係噉，下次
(en) Alright, next time...
(yue)50年之後，我知有個睇得更加清楚嘅地方
(en) In 50 years, I know of a place where the view is even clearer.
(yue)我帶你哋去吖
(en) I'll take you there.
(yue)笑咩啊？
(en) What are you laughing at?
(yue)冇
(en) Nothing.
(yue)咩事都冇啊
(en) There's really nothing.
(yue)就噉話啦
(en) That's what I meant.
(yue)大家一齊去睇
(en) Let's all go and see.
(yue)係噉，喺度講再見喇
(en) Alright then, it's time to say goodbye here.
(yue)跟住你有咩打算啊？
(en) What are you planning to do next?
(yue)我諗住繼續收集魔法
(en) I intend to keep collecting magic.
(yue)我預計會用一百年左右行勻成個中央諸國
(en) I anticipate spending roughly a hundred years traveling throughout the central nations.
(yue)不過，我間中會揾下你哋𠸏
(en) However, I'll occasionally seek you out.
(yue)精靈嘅時間觀念真係好難理解
(en) The elves' perception of time is truly hard to understand.
(yue)咪係囖，佢究竟可以生存幾耐呢？
(en) Indeed, just how long can they survive?
(yue)無論係50年定100年，對佢嚟講
(en) Whether it's 50 or 100 years, to them
(yue)或者都只係一啲微不足道嘅時間
(en) is merely a negligible span of time.
(yue)你話暗黑龍嘅角？
(en) Are you referring to the Dark Dragon's horn?
(yue)我哋鋪頭冇賣呢樣嘢啝
(en) Our store doesn't carry such an item.
(yue)就算係暗黑龍都已經二三十年冇見過喇
(en) Even the Dark Dragon hasn't been seen for twenty or thirty years.
(yue)係呀？噉就麻煩喇
(en) Really? That could be problematic.
(yue)召喚嗰陣要用㗎
(en) It's needed for summoning.
(yue)係喎，之前係魔王城執到嘅角
(en) Right, it was the horn we obtained from the Demon King's castle.
(yue)應該仲放喺欣梅爾嗰度
(en) It should still be kept with Xinmel.
(yue)硬係覺得佢散發住好邪惡嘅氣息啊
(en) I just feel that it emanates a truly sinister aura.
(yue)但係應該對人冇害㗎嗬？
(en) But it probably doesn't harm people, does it?
(yue)我唔知啊
(en) I don't know.
(yue)連你都唔知呀？
(en) Even you don't know?
(yue)就嚟又到半世紀流星嘅時候
(en) Soon, it will be time for the half-century meteor again.
(yue)順便睇下佢點樣啦
(en) Might as well see how it turns out.
(yue)同上次嚟嗰陣比條街真係唔同咗好多
(en) The street has changed so much compared to the last time.
(yue)我記得喺呢度附近㗎喎
(en) I recall it being around here.
(yue)芙莉蓮？
(en) Flilian?
(yue)欣梅爾？
(en) Xinmel?
(yue)你老咗好多啊
(en) You've aged significantly.
(yue)講嘢咁過分㗎
(en) You speak too harshly.
(yue)就算我而家老咗，都仲幾俊俏吖
(en) Even though I'm old now, I'm still quite dashing.
(yue)已經50年冇見喇
(en) It's been 50 years since we last met.
(yue)你個樣仲係同以前一模一樣
(en) You still look exactly the same as before.
(yue)我仲以為呢一世都唔會再見到你喇
(en) I had thought I would never see you again in this life.
(yue)半世紀流星呀？
(en) The half-century meteor, huh?
(yue)好令人懷念啊
(en) It's so reminiscent.
(yue)仲有就係關於係魔王城執到嘅嗰樣嘢
(en) And also, about that thing we retrieved from the Demon King's castle.
(yue)你係咪講咁黑龍嘅角啊？
(en) Are you referring to the Dark Dragon's horn?
(yue)關於呢樣嘢，我從來都冇忘記過
(en) I have never forgotten about it.
(yue)因為佢一直喺個櫃裏面散發邪惡嘅氣息
(en) Because it has always exuded an evil aura from within the cabinet.
(yue)真係唔好意思
(en) I'm truly sorry.
(yue)其實你求其揾個倉庫
放佢入去唔理佢咪得囖
(en) Actually, you could simply find a warehouse and put it away, and not worry about it.
(yue)噉樣點得嗄？
(en) That won't do, will it?
(yue)對你嚟講，或者佢可能
只係一樣隨便寄放喺我度嘅嘢
(en) To you, it might simply be something you casually leave with me,
(yue)但係對我嚟講
(en) But for me,
(yue)佢係重要嘅同伴託付畀我嘅貴重物品嚟𠿪
(en) it is a valuable item entrusted to me by an important comrade.
(yue)我一直都諗住將來有日可以將佢還返畀你
(en) I've always planned to return it to you someday.
(yue)明明呢樣嘢根本就一啲都唔重要
(en) Clearly, this thing is not important at all.
(yue)欣梅爾仲未得嗱？
(en) Has Xinmel not arrived yet?
(yue)你冇頭髮花時間打扮都冇意思啦
(en) Without hair, there's no point in spending time on styling.
(yue)光頭都有光頭嘅堅持㗎
(en) Even a bald head has its own sense of pride.
(yue)好喇
(en) Alright.
(yue)我哋而家去睇半世紀流星喇
(en) Let's go see the half-century meteor now.
(yue)你變到好有威嚴喎，海塔
(en) You've become so dignified, Haita.
(yue)因為我係聖都嘅主教啊
(en) Because I am the bishop of the Holy City.
(yue)芙莉蓮，你真係一啲都冇變啊
(en) Flilian, you really haven't changed at all.
(yue)唔好摸我個頭啦
(en) Don't touch my head.
(yue)艾冉你個樣冇乜點變過啊
(en) Airan, you haven't changed much.
(yue)係咩？睇落冇變呀？
(en) Really? You seem unchanged.
(yue)不愧係矮人族啊
(en) As expected of the dwarves.
(yue)係噉，你話睇得更加清嘅地方喺邊啊？
(en) So, where is that place with a clearer view?
(yue)嗯？
(en) Hmm?
(yue)而家就出發去呀？
(en) Shall we set off now?
(yue)距離出現半世紀流星嘅時期
(en) There is still some time until the half-century meteor appears,
(yue)應該仲有段時間喎
(en) it should be a while.
(yue)嗯
(en) Hmm.
(yue)因為要由呢度行一個禮拜過去㗎
(en) Because it takes about a week to walk from here.
(yue)咩話？要行咁遠？
(en) What? We have to walk that far?
(yue)真係吖，噉折磨老人家㗎
(en) Indeed, that's truly tormenting for us old folks.
(yue)好懷念啊
(en) I miss those days.
(yue)而家噉樣行，就好似返返去嗰陣噉
(en) Walking like this feels just like the old days.
(yue)我哋去咗好多唔同嘅地方旅行
(en) We've journeyed to many different places.
(yue)所有嘢都覺得好新鮮
(en) Everything felt so new.
(yue)而且睇落好耀眼
(en) And it looked dazzling.
(yue)喺我咁多美麗嘅回憶入面
(en) Among all my beautiful memories,
(yue)一直都有你哋陪住我
(en) you've always been there for me.
(yue)我一直
(en) I've always
(yue)都好期待我哋所有人可以再次聚埋一齊㗎
(en) eagerly anticipating the day when all of us can reunite.
(yue)好多謝你啊，芙莉蓮
(en) Thank you so much, Flilian.
(yue)都係多得你
(en) It's all thanks to you.
(yue)我先可以體驗到最後一次開心嘅冒險
(en) Because of you, I was able to experience one final, joyful adventure.
(yue)好靚啊
(en) So beautiful.
(yue)欣梅爾佢，就嗰陣一定覺得好幸福㗎喇
(en) Xinmel must have felt incredibly blessed back then.
(yue)真係噉咩？
(en) Really?
(yue)聽講嗰個女仔係欣梅爾大人嘅同伴嚟啊
(en) I heard that the girl is a companion of Lord Xinmel.
(yue)但係睇落一啲都唔傷心𠸏
(en) Yet she doesn't appear sorrowful at all.
(yue)真係好無情啊
(en) Truly heartless.
(yue)哎吔…
(en) Oh dear...
(yue)我哋兩個睇落都唔傷心喎
(en) The two of us don't seem sad either.
(yue)主教，你莊重啲啦
(en) Bishop, be more dignified.
(yue)你真係冇人性啊！
(en) You truly lack any humanity!
(yue)畀人秒殺啊
(en) You got taken out in seconds.
(yue)因為我根本…
(en) Because I simply...
(yue)一啲都唔了解欣梅爾佢
(en) don't understand Xinmel at all.
(yue)我哋只不過係…
(en) We are simply...
(yue)一齊旅行咗十年吒嘛
(en) having traveled together for ten years.
(yue)我明明知道人類嘅壽命
(en) I clearly know that the lifespan of humans
(yue)不嬲都好短
(en) have always been very short.
(yue)點解冇諗過…
(en) Why didn't we ever consider...
(yue)多啲去了解下佢呢？
(en) getting to understand them more?
(yue)唔好摸我個頭啦
(en) Don't touch my head.
(yue)我都係時候要返去聖都㗎喇
(en) It's time for me to head back to the Holy City.
(yue)等我再好好睇下你哋個樣啦
(en) Let me take one more good look at your faces.
(yue)今次係我哋最後一次見面喇
(en) This is our final meeting.
(yue)你係咪唔舒服啊？
(en) Are you feeling unwell?
(yue)飲酒飲得太痛搞到周身病痛
(en) Drinking too much has left you in pain all over.
(yue)而家報應到哩？
(en) Is karma finally catching up?
(yue)如果你哋有日去開聖都，記得帶支酒
(en) If you ever visit the Holy City, remember to bring some wine.
(yue)去我墳度拜我啊
(en) and pay homage at my grave.
(yue)海塔你，真係一啲都唔驚死咩？
(en) Haita, are you truly not afraid of death?
(yue)我哋幾個係拯救世界嘅勇者隊成員嚟𠺢嘛
(en) We are members of the heroic team that saved the world, after all.
(yue)死咗之後，唔使問一定係上天堂享福
(en) After death, there's no question we'll be enjoying heaven.
(yue)我都係為咗噉樣
(en) That's precisely why I
(yue)先會同你哋一齊去戰鬥㗎咋
(en) ended up fighting with you all.
(yue)你個酒肉和尚
(en) You meat-eating monk.
(yue)係噉，我走先喇
(en) Alright, I'm leaving now.
(yue)好啦，我都係時候要走喇
(en) Alright, it's time for me to leave too.
(yue)繼續收集魔法之類？
(en) Continue collecting magic or something?
(yue)嗯，呢個都係目的之一
(en) Yes, that's one of my purposes.
(yue)但係我仲想去試下多啲了解人類
(en) But I also want to try to understand humans better.
(yue)乜係？
(en) What?
(yue)我有一件事想同你商量啊
(en) I have something I'd like to discuss with you.
(yue)因為我係用魔法𠺢嘛
(en) Because I use magic,
(yue)所以如果身邊有個強大嘅先鋒就好喇
(en) so it would be nice to have a strong vanguard by my side.
(yue)你都係放過我啦
(en) You should just let me be.
(yue)我已經年紀大到揮唔郁把斧頭喇
(en) I'm already too old to even swing an axe.
(yue)唔好噉嘅表情啦，芙莉蓮
(en) Don't make that face, Flilian.
(yue)人嘅一生喺歲老之後嘅時間
(en) The later part of one's life after aging
(yue)比想象中要長嘅
(en) is longer than we think.
(yue)係呀？
(en) Really?
(yue)噉再見喇，艾冉
(en) Well then, goodbye, Airan.
(yue)啊，再見
(en) Ah, goodbye.
(yue)（第一話：冒險結束）
(en) (Episode One: The Adventure Ends)
(yue)係頭先棵樹呀？
(en) Was that the tree from earlier?
(yue)每次嚟呢個森林都會蕩失路
(en) Every time I come to this forest, I end up getting lost.
(yue)呢度係邊度啊？
(en) Where is this place?
(yue)（勇者欣梅爾死之後20年）
（中央諸國）
（聖都修特拉爾郊外）
(en) (20 years after Hero Xinmel's death)
(Central Nations)
(Outskirts of the Holy City, Xiu Telar)
(yue)請問你係咪揾緊咩啊？
(en) Excuse me, are you searching for something?
(yue)請問係咪有咩事啊？
(en) May I ask, is there a problem?
(yue)噉𠸏，我喺度揾緊一個
叫海塔嘅人嘅屋企啊
(en) Well, I'm looking for the house of someone named Haita.
(yue)原來你係海塔大人嘅客人呀？
(en) So you're a guest of Lord Haita?
(yue)你個酒肉和尚仲好地地喎
(en) You, the meat-eating monk, are still quite decent.
(yue)想好有型噉死
(en) Want to go out in style.
(yue)都唔係件容易嘅事嚟㗎
(en) That's not an easy thing to do.
(yue)我仲買咗酒諗住放喺你個墳前面
(en) I even bought some wine, intending to place it in front of your grave.
(yue)飲唔飲返杯啊？
(en) Care for a drink?
(yue)我已經戒咗酒喇
(en) I've already quit drinking.
(yue)係呀？
(en) Really?
(yue)而家先開始改過自新
(en) I'm only now beginning to reform.
(yue)我諗女神大人應該都唔會就噉原諒你
(en) I don't think the Goddess would simply forgive you just like that.
(yue)真係唔該晒你啊
(en) Thank you so much.
(yue)佢係邊個啊？
(en) Who is he?
(yue)佢個名叫做費倫
(en) His name is Feilun.
(yue)係南方諸國嘅戰爭留落嚟嘅孤兒
(en) An orphan left over from the wars in the southern nations.
(yue)好唔似你喎
(en) That doesn't quite match you.
(yue)你不嬲都唔係嗰種會熱心助人嘅人嚟
(en) You've never been the kind of person who's eager to help others.
(yue)同欣梅爾好唔同
(en) Not at all like Xinmel.
(yue)芙莉蓮，你嚟我呢度做咩啊？
(en) Flilian, what brings you here?
(yue)我去聖都買嘢順便嚟睇你
(en) I went to the Holy City to shop, and I took the opportunity to see you.
(yue)因為我而家會盡量
同旅途中遇到嘅人多啲互動
(en) Because these days, I try to interact more with the people I meet on my journeys.
(yue)再加上，我仲爭海塔你好多人情
(en) Moreover, I still owe you a lot of favors, Haita.
(yue)所以想喺你死之前還畀你
(en) So I wish to return something to you before you pass away.
(yue)係噉有件事想拜託你
(en) I have a request for you.
(yue)嗯？
(en) Hmm?
(yue)你有冇諗過收徒弟？
(en) Have you ever thought about taking on an apprentice?
(yue)費倫佢，好有做一個魔法師嘅資質
(en) Feilun has the aptitude to be a great magician.
(yue)你可唔可以帶埋佢同你一齊去旅行啊？
(en) Could you take him along with you on your journey?
(yue)對唔住啊，海塔
(en) I'm sorry, Haita.
(yue)我冇辦法應承你
(en) I can't commit to that.
(yue)佢會成為我嘅負累
(en) He would just become a liability to me.
(yue)你都知見習魔法師
喺實戰嘅死亡率有幾高㗎啦
(en) You know how high the death rate is for apprentice magicians in battle.
(yue)朋友交託個細路畀我
(en) A friend entrusted me with the youngster.
(yue)我唔打算送佢去死啊
(en) I don't intend to let him die.
(yue)原來係噉
(en) I see.
(yue)係噉，我想拜託你另一件事
(en) Alright, I have another favor to ask of you.
(yue)呢本係由賢者埃維希個墓出土嘅文物
(en) This book is an artifact excavated from the tomb of the sage Evishi.
(yue)聽講呢本魔道書
(en) I heard that this grimoire
(yue)入面記載住而家已經失傳咗
(en) contains inscriptions that are now lost.
(yue)可以將死者復活嘅不死魔法
(en) The necromancy that can revive the dead.
(yue)我唔覺得呢個世界上會有呢啲噉嘅魔法囖
(en) I don't believe such magic exists in this world.
(yue)所以我想你幫我手解讀呢個魔道書
(en) So I want you to help me decipher this grimoire.
(yue)可唔可以啊？
(en) Can you do that?
(yue)呢啲係用圖畫做嘅暗號？
(en) Are these secret codes made out of drawings?
(yue)呢個時代嘅人真係好鍾意呢啲嘢
(en) People in this era really have a fondness for these things.
(yue)只要畀五六年我都得𠸏
(en) I could manage it in just five or six years.
(yue)係噉樣呀？
(en) Is that so?
(yue)但係解讀呢啲嘢之後，你打算做咩啊？
(en) But after deciphering these, what do you intend to do?
(yue)你之前唔係話過你唔怕死㗎咩？
(en) Didn't you say that you weren't afraid of death?
(yue)我噉做係有兩個理由
(en) I have two reasons for doing this.
(yue)第一個係
(en) The first is
(yue)我之前喺你哋面前噉講即係讕有型
(en) that my previous words in front of you were merely for show.
(yue)另一個理由係我比起之前變得更加怕死
(en) The other reason is that I have grown more fearful of death than before.
(yue)我唔使長生不死
(en) I don't need eternal life.
(yue)只想長命啲
(en) I only wish to live a bit longer.
(yue)長少少已經夠㗎喇
(en) A little extra longevity is enough.
(yue)我想要多啲啲時間
(en) I desire more time.
(yue)而且聖典都有寫啦
(en) And the scriptures also mention it.
(yue)人要健健康康噉生活
(en) That people should live healthily.
(yue)長壽咪係最好嘅證明囖，芙莉蓮
(en) Longevity is the greatest testament, Flilian.
(yue)你個酒肉和尚
(en) You meat-eating monk.
(yue)啊，係喇
(en) Ah, indeed.
(yue)喺你解讀嘅空檔時間都冇問題㗎
(en) There's no issue as long as it fits into the gaps during your deciphering.
(yue)你可唔可以幫手教下費倫佢點用魔法啊？
(en) Could you help instruct Feilun on how to use magic?
(yue)因為我係個僧侶
(en) Because I'm a monk.
(yue)所以真係唔係好識教佢
(en) So I'm not very good at teaching him.
(yue)如果淨係教下都得𠸏
(en) Even just teaching him the basics would suffice.
(yue)揾到喇
(en) Found it.
(yue)要揾你真係唔容易啊
(en) It's really not easy to find you.
(yue)你平時都係喺森林修行嘎？
(en) Do you normally practice in the forest?
(yue)原來就連芙莉蓮大人
你都覺得好難先可以揾到我呀？
(en) So even Lord Flilian finds it difficult to locate me?
(yue)海塔大人成日都話
(en) Lord Haita always says
(yue)我呢個人冇乜存在感
(en) that I don't have much presence.
(yue)但係我覺得噉樣唔算係一件壞事
(en) But I think that's not necessarily a bad thing.
(yue)你都啱𠸏
(en) You're right.
(yue)果然...
(en) As expected...
(yue)魔力探知對佢冇乜反應咁滯
(en) Magical detection has little effect on him.
(yue)佢操控魔力嘅技術好出色
(en) His technique in manipulating magic is outstanding.
(yue)佢咁細個
(en) When he was just a child,
(yue)究竟用咗幾多時間去鑽研魔法啊？
(en) just how much time did he spend delving into magic?
(yue)海塔大人話
(en) Lord Haita said,
(yue)我打得穿山頂嗰嚿岩石
(en) I could break through that mountain-top boulder,
(yue)就可以自己獨當一面㗎喇
(en) then I could manage on my own.
(yue)吓？
(en) Huh?
(yue)海塔都識啲嘢喎
(en) Haita does know a thing or two.
(yue)嗰嚿係...
(en) That boulder is...
(yue)我嘅魔力會好似噉樣散開晒
(en) My magic will spread out like this completely,
(yue)去唔到嗰嚿石
(en) and won't affect that boulder.
(yue)原來係噉樣
(en) So that's how it works.
(yue)係噉我應該點樣修行先至好啊？
(en) So how should I train properly then?
(yue)喂
(en) Hey.
(yue)我想問你一樣嘢先
(en) I want to ask you something first.
(yue)你鍾唔鍾意魔法？
(en) Do you like magic?
(yue)我諗我都算鍾意𠸏
(en) I suppose I do.
(yue)同我一模一樣啊
(en) Just like me.
(yue)（第二話，不見得一定是靠魔法…）
唔係一定要靠魔法㗎
(en) (Episode Two: It Isn't Necessarily About Relying on Magic...)
It's not all about relying on magic.